Matheus Torquato

Computer Engineer, MSc.

Contact

Summary

Swansea, Wales United Kingdom

Matheusft@gmail.com

Expertise

Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Data Science, Data Mining, Embedded Computing, Digital Systems, Reconfigurable Computing and Human-Computer Interaction.

Skills

Python, MATLAB, TensorFlow, Scikit Learn. Pandas. NumPy, SciPy, Version control systems, Translating complex scientific concepts to non-experts, Proactivity, Organisation, Communication, Responsibility and Discipline

Languages

English Portuguese

BEng and MSc in Computer Engineering. Two years of experience in applying Machine Learning to manufacturing processes. Expertise in scientific and applied research in the topics of Artificial Intelligence, Data Science, Embedded Computing, Digital Systems and Human-Computer Interaction. Well-developed skills employing scientific methods through experimental design, exploratory data analysis and hypothesis testing. Enthusiastic about utilising novel analytical approaches to address real-world challenges and improve commercial outcomes with data. Looking to learn on a daily basis, knowledge is never too much.

Experience

2018-Now **ASTUTE 2020**

Project Assistant (Machine Learning) - June to Now

- · Leading the development of projects involving machine learning, data science, computer vision and optimisation.
- Designing regression, classification and predictive models for different processes in the Welsh manufacturing sector.
- Delivering actionable insights from industrial datasets focusing on supporting managerial informed decisions.

2015-2015 **Tata Steel**

Process Control Engineering Trainee - September to October

- - Developed a mobile app (VB programming language) for logging field measurements, previously performed manually.
 - Collaborated in the selection of power metering devices for updating the company's high voltage substation network.

2014-2014 **Petrobras**

Natal, RN, Brazil Engineering Intern - March to May

· Assisted in the final stage of a Programmable Logic Controller ladder code development.

2014-2014 **National Institute for Space Research (INPE)**

Engineering Intern - January to March

· Coded a frequency-based signal detecting software (MATLAB) used by low altitude satellites.

Education

Swansea, Wales, UK

Port Talbot, Wales, UK

Natal, RN, Brazil

2016-2017	Masters in Computer Engineering Final Mark: 10/10 Included A Period in The SMART Lab (Ottawa, Canada) As A Visiting Researcher.
2014-2015	Undergraduate in Computer Science Swansea University - Swansea, Wales Final Mark: 7.1/10 Scholarship Awarded from The Science Without Borders Programme
2013–2015	Undergraduate in Computer Engineering UFRN - Brazil Final Mark: 9.6/10 Result Among the Top 0.16% Highest in The History of This Undergraduate Course.

Additional Activities

2020	Coding Project Development Github Modelling ML
2020	Online Course Quantitative Finance & Algorithmic Trading in Python
2019	Online Course Python for Financial Analysis and Algorithmic Trading
2018	Online Course University of Michigan - edX Introduction to User Experience
2015	Volunteer Researcher Future Interaction Technology Lab - Swansea University Volunteer Researcher in the field of Human-Computer Interaction.
2014	Research Project Machine Learning and Intelligent Instrumentation Laboratory - UFRN Embedded Applications Using Microcontrollers and FPGA.
2013	Research Project Computer Engineering Department - UFRN Using Computational Tools in Wind Turbine Study.

Publications

2020	Journal Paper Evaluating the burden of COVID-19 on hospital resources in Bahia, Brazil: A modelling-based analysis of 14.8 million individuals.
2019	Journal Paper Circuits, Systems, and Signal Processing High-Performance Parallel Implementation of Genetic Algorithm on FPGA.
2019	Journal Paper Parallel Implementation of Reinforcement Learning Q-Learning Technique for FPGA.
2019	Journal Paper Deep Neural Network Hardware Implementation Based on Stacked Sparse Autoencoder.
2016	Journal Paper - (Honorable Mention) CHI 2016 Emergeables: Deformable Displays for Continuous Eyes-Free Mobile Interaction